RANJU RAVEENDRAN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Auckland, New Zealand 02102467215 ranjurave@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ranjurave www.github.com/ranjurave www.ranjurave.com

CICD

Unity

REST API

Unreal Engine

A passionate developer who has worked in a variety of areas, including Web Development, Game Development, XR Development, and Computer Graphics. I hold a degree in Computer Science and have completed an Advanced Software Developer course, as well as a Master's in Creative Technologies. Throughout my career, I have consistently demonstrated my ability to rapidly grasp new technologies and perform effectively even under pressure. My areas of expertise include Full Stack Development, Game & App Development, and 3D Graphics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C++ HTML
C# CSS
Python JavaScript
.NET Node.js
SQL Server React

SQL Server React Adobe Creative Suit

MongoDB Git Maya

EXPERIENCES

Yoobee College, Auckland

Software Engineering Lecturer

February 2018 to Present

Deliver courses to year 2 and year 3 students of Bachelor of Software Engineering.

- Design and deliver courses to NZQA standards
- Coach and guide final-year students in completing Web and Game Development projects.
- Delivering the following courses:
 - Web app development in Python and Flask
 - Programming C# and C++
 - Game development using Unreal Engine and Unity
 - 3D Content Creation

Niramsoft

Freelance Software Developer

July 2021 to Present

- Develop Web Applications
- Develop Mobile AR Applications
- Develop Game Prototypes

Native Software, Tauranga

Software Developer Intern

October 2022 to December 2022.

- Worked with React, C#, SQL and .NET
- Developed a Web API for a bespoke ticket-tracking system
- Connected APIs from different ticketing systems to the backend

Achievement: Completed all features using the .NET framework as per the software specification document with no assistance from the mentors and manager.

Huhu Studios, Snells Beach, Auckland

Senior Animator / Generalist

September 2010 to January 2018

- Performed scripting in Maya Embedded Library (MEL)
- Created 3D models in Maya
- Rigged character and prop models for animation
- Performed scene layout and set dressing
- Created 3D animations

Achievement: Started as a junior animator and progressed to become a senior animator. Assisted other departments, including modelling and rigging, during periods of staff shortage.

EDUCATION

Advanced Software Developer (Level 6 NZQA) – Oct to Dec 2022 Software Developer - AI & Cloud (Level 5) – Aug to Sep 2022 Full Stack Developer (Level 4) – May to July 2022

Mission Ready HQ, Auckland

Master of Creative Technologies (Honours) - 2020 - 2021

Auckland University of Technology, Auckland

Bachelor of Computer Science - 1998 - 2001

AJ College of Science and Technology, Kerala University, India

SOFT SKILLS

Communication - written and verbal Research

Team Player Analytical Skills
Fast Learner Problem Solving
Team Management Attention to Detail

REFERENCES

References can be provided on request.